Nicole **Mazzuca**

nicole@strega-nil.co | +1 (425) 443-3734

ABOUT ME

I am a software engineer who has long been fascinated by developer tooling and programming languages. I had an early start in the Rust community, then switched over to C++ six years ago. I absolutely love developer tooling for its customer-facing nature, and for the impact I can make in a customer's every-day experience.

EDUCATION

B.Sc. in Mathematics

Western Washington University January 2018 - December 2019 New York University Fall 2016

Associate of Art

Bellevue College – Running Start September 2014 - July 2016

LINKS

閾 @strega-nil

@ @streganil

in Nicole Mazzuca

SKILLS

Expert in Modern C++ Experienced in Rust Experienced in CMake Competent in OCaml Competent in JavaScript Competent in Python

ACHIEVEMENTS

Spoke at CppCon 2017 and 2018 Helped run CSAW 2016

EXPERIENCE

Microsoft – Visual C++ Libraries - Software Engineer May 2022 - De

May 2022 - December 2023

- Maintainer of the Microsoft Visual C++ Standard Library
- Code reviewed pull requests from open source contributors and colleagues
- Implemented C++ standard papers P2494R2, P2408R5, P2517R1, and P2520R0
- Supported the Windows internal C++ toolset updates
- Created a process for community members to add subtitles to our Video Code Reviews
- Address Sanitizer libraries implementor
 - Communicated with internal teams to discover issues and necessary features
 - Lead Standard Library/Address Sanitizer compatibility efforts especially std::string ASan integration

Microsoft – vcpkg - Software Engineer

January 2020 - May 2022

- Designed and implemented multiple major features which were blockers for enterprise customers and Visual Studio integration
 - Registries
 - Manifests
 - Localization
- · Lead efforts to open lines of communication with community members
 - Added a #include <C++> channel for vcpkg
 - Worked to create an agreement for timely PR review
 - Created the vcpkg RFC process
- Lead the macOS pull request testing infrastructure efforts
- Code reviewed pull requests from open source contributors and colleagues

Microsoft – vcpkg - Software Engineering Intern

July 2019 - August 2019

- Rewrote parts of the filesystem layer
- Rewrote the tests to be cross-platform using Catch2
- · Added benchmarks to the tool
- Added hashing code to avoid calling out to platform-specific tools Sha1, Sha256, and Sha512

SIGNIFICANT PROJECTS

#include <C++> 2018 -

- Founding member of, and moderator for, the #include <C++> community the largest chatroom for C++ developers.
- We have a long-standing commitment for inclusion and diversity in the C++ community.
- Additionally, as part of my time in vcpkg, we opened an official vcpkg channel in the #include <C++> discord.

vcpkg Manifests

May - September 2020

- I lead the charge on designing and implementing the manifests feature from its initial RFC to completion.
- Completely changed how users interact with vcpkg, while still supporting strict backwards compatibility with existing usecases
- The necessary first step towards bringing the C++ package management experience in line with other languages, with both package versioning and user-local installation fully depending on manifests.

vcpkg Registries

September 2020 - March 2021

- Another major feature, necessary for enterprise customers, closed source libraries, and package versioning.
- Again, lead the charge on designing and implementing.
- Well-loved by the community: "[about registries] Isn't that beautiful. With Conan I couldn't come up with a working setup for this, and with vcpkg it just works with a minimal effort." (from this blog post)